Okay. So, how do we get an item out of
um session or local storage? In other
words, how do we retrieve data? So, if
we come over here to application, I've
actually added a second number and a
number and a key for hello. Um, so I've
got a key for hello, a key for second
num and a key for num. And in session
storage, I have this hello key. So, if I
want to access an item, then what I do
is I say local storage.get get item
and then I put in the key that I'm
trying to get. So let's say I'm trying
to get hello. If I put that in, it
retrieves world and I could actually
store that in a variable. So I could say
let my var equal local storage.get item
hello.
And now if I console.log
log my var.
You can see that it logs out the word
world just like we would expect. So
that's great. Um that's how we get an
item. Um and you do the same thing for
session storage. So I could say
console.log
session
boy can't spell session
storage.get
get
item and we could put in the hello key
that we put into session storage
and we get world from there as well. And
if we went and checked our application,
you could see that we're storing hello
world and session storage. So we are
able to store items in session storage
and we were able to retrieve them.
Remember the caveat I said that
everything that is stored in session
storage is a string. If you come back
over here and you look in local storage,
um it has second num which has a value
of two. So if I console.log
the type of
local storage.get
item
number,
then I get that it is a string. Even
though when we look in the application
it looks like it'd be a number, it is in
fact a string. And so if we want it to
be a number, we just have to convert